I never in a million years would have imaginedthat I would be
standing here today. The first experience that I had with Exxon
was througha scholarship that they offered and I wrote an
essay about how I wanted to find substitutesfor
petroleum-based plastics; when I got the notification saying
that I had been selected, Iwas blown out of the water.
There's been so many opportunities that Exxon has provided
me so I'veactually spoken to members of Congress about what
it is like to be a woman in STEM. I was sittingnext to the
president of Emory yesterday, and so getting that kind of
interaction and being ableto pick their brains is something that I
think is a really cool opportunity.
I really like thelab because it kind of takes that like passion for
learning and then also that passion for doingthings.
There's a couple big projects, one is algae biofuels
and carbon capture sequestration, onething that I think is
really cool about Exxon is that the work that you're doing
isn't just foryourself, it's really for the whole world and so
hopefully I'll be part of one of those teams maybesomeday.
Being an engineer, sometimes bridging that gap of what you
don't understand and takingit into the realm of it can
be described by math and physics, but also truly appreciating
the artbehind it. Being at Exxon, you work with the best people,
people who are diverse in thought and background.
When you're new engineer, you might be afraid that you don't
have the knowledge level, theexperience to make a difference
but here I've only been pushed to change the status quo.
As a childinto my middle school and high school years, one
of the things I really enjoyed doing was actuallywatching
the History Channel. They would have these kind of special
episodes that were titled engineeringdisasters and that's really
what started to get me into the field of safety.
I never thought Iwould be in the shoes of somebody who has
the responsibility of protecting our community'sco-workers
and our facilities, and being able to make an actual impact,
an actual change ina way that I think makes a big difference
I saw an opportunity for an ocean engineering program,
which I didn't really know what it meant but it seemed like it fit
my love for being on the water,and wanting to do engineering.
My senior year of undergrad I met somebody from ExxonMobil,
cameto watch the presentations and we struck up a
conversation and he actually was a bit of amentor to me,
then following my internship, I was hired on full-time.
Engineers and operations isa program that all of the upstream
engineering new hires would go into, so essentially youare
put out rotating to an operating asset where you're able
to experience operationswith mechanics, electricians,
operators, and you don't have any engineering responsibilities.
I think it set me up really well moving forward in my career and
I just wanted to give thatopportunity to other people and
coordinate the next year. It really allows me to see
how what I do affects the corporation overall.
The biggest thing about me is really around helping people.
I never saw the energy industry as a place that I wanted to work
I decided to do a summerexperience and an internship with
ExxonMobil at the Baytown chemical plants and
I really loved that experience.
The world is growing and we're gonna have 9 billion people
in the worldby 2040 and how do you supply energy to all of
these people. I think the work that we do here isimportant,
It's always something new, and that variety
in my work life is something that I love.
I'm anupstream unconventionals reservoir engineering intern
and I'm helping the team understand andconstantly evaluate
the Wells performance. Being on the forefront of some of these
technologiesand using them to really help assist you as
an engineer has really helped. About a month intothe
internship, my manager came to me and asked me if I'd like to
go with the team to Canadaand I was thrilled. Somehow they
made it work for me which really meant a lot to me.
I got tomeet face to face some of the people in Canada that
I always see their names on the morningcalls and
say oh hi I'm the intern and this is what I'm working on,
I just really felt like wow this teamis kind of a family, if I commit
to a career with a company, I hope that they'd commit to me
as welland based on the people I've met here that is very true.
Growing up I participated in math and sciencecompetition
sponsored by ExxonMobil. I actually took a trip as a kid
to the ExxonMobil refinery, youknow that gave me the dream
or the longing to say in the future I want to be
part of this company. Growing up in Nigeria, I witnessed
the malaria initiative by ExxonMobil, all the kids that we
have beneficiaries of that malaria initiative eventually went
to school and eventually becamesuccessful.
The names on this wall inspires innovation to me, knowing
that all thesepeople were able to deliver tangible milestones
for the company. I want to see my name on thewall knowing
that I was part of this dynamic company that improves human
lives throughinnovation and corporate social responsibility